(cezanne camacho) Hey there.
Welcome to Advanced Android.
My name is Cezanne
Camacho, and in this lesson
we'll be learning
about fragments.
Fragments are Android
app components
that represent a
self-contained portion of user
interface in an activity.
You can think of them
as mini-activities.
We'll learn all about
fragments in this lesson
by working together to
build an app that uses them.
We'll be building an app
called Android Me that
lets us create and customize
the appearance of an Android
by giving it different
hairstyles, clothing,
and accessories.
I've already provided some
starting code for this app,
and I'll walk through that soon.
For now, know that
we'll be using
sets of images that let
us choose the head, body,
and leg portions of the
Android individually.
We'll also be following
the principles
of responsive design, which
means that we'll build our app
to look great across a variety
of different screen sizes.
Next, we'll see
how fragments can
help us build responsive
and flexible layouts.