Since the master
list fragment will not
change during the
activity's run time,
it is considered
a static fragment.
And I can place it in a layout
using the fragment tag instead
of a transaction.
The fragment should have a name
and a width and height, just
like a typical view.
And the name is
actually going to point
to the type of fragment this is.
And I've given it the
ID, master list fragment.
Finally I'll create a
new main activity that
displays this activity layout.
In here, I'll override
the uncreate method
and set the content view.
The last step in
this exercise will
be to declare this activity
in the Android manifest file
and set it to default launch.
Let's see what it looks like.
Here's what the
app looks like now.
In the next exercise, you'll
be given minor guidance
on completing and displaying
this list of images.
By the end of the
exercise, you should
have a list of all
our images that looks
like this on a phone screen.
After this section, we'll
work on communicating
between fragments and
their host activities.