Our next task will
be to communicate
between our MasterList
and BodyPartFragments.
And this can get
a little tricky.
We already know that the real
advantage to using fragments
is their modularity
and reusability.
So to build them for
maximum reusability,
we should make each
fragment self-contained.
This just means that a
single fragment will also
contain code that defines
its layout and behavior, when
it comes to user interaction.
And it also means that,
generally, fragments
can never directly
communicate with one another.
But then, how can you
communicate between two
self-contained fragments?
Well, all fragment to
fragment communication
can be done through
a shared activity.
To give a fragment the ability
to communicate up to its host
activity, it's good
practice to define
an interface in
the fragment class,
and implement it
within the activity.
This is easier to
understand in code.
So let's jump in and
define an interface.