To communicate
between a fragment and its host
activity, you can define an
interface in the fragment class
and implement
within the activity.
So let's do this to
have our master list
fragment communicate
with the main activity.
To define an interface
we'll create a listener
in our master list fragment.
You can name it anything.
I'm calling it
onimageclicklistener,
and giving it the
variable m callback.
This will eventually be
implemented in the host
activity, and there
we can program
it to perform some
action whenever
a list image is clicked.
Then, to define this interface
we just specify the method
that it triggers.
Here we're having
it trigger method
called on image selected.
This takes an int
variable position,
which will just be the position
that a user clicks on our grid
view.
We also have to make sure that
the host activity implements
the callback.
And we can check
in the master list
fragments on attach method.
This is where a
fragment attaches itself
to its host activity.
Then it checks to see
that the image click
listener is implemented,
and if it's not it
throws an exception.
Lastly, in oncreate view, we
need to trigger the callback
on a click.
So we'll set a click
listener on the grid view,
and call the callback
method onimageselected
whenever an item in our
grid view is clicked.
Then we can pass in the
clicked position too.
Now that we've defined this
interface in our fragment,
let's link it to
our main activity.
I mentioned that in order
to receive callbacks
from the master list
fragment, the main activity
must implement the interface we
defined in the fragment class.
So right at the top we
write implementmasterl
istfragment.onim
ageclicklistener.
Then you can see
we get an error,
because this means we
also need to implement
the method on image selected.
So let's define the behavior
for on image selected.
And this is where we'll
handle fragment communication.
This interface acts a lot
like a custom click listener.
It's triggered in
the fragment class,
and performs some action
in the host activity.
For now in on image
selected, I've
created a Toast to see
if we've implemented
this communication correctly.
It should display a message
about the position clicked
when an image is selected.
Let's try it out.
Now you should see
a short Toast appear
every time I click on an
image in the master list.
The positions range from
0 all the way down to 35.
Next, it will be your turn
to complete this code,
and successfully
implement fragment
to activity communication.