Now that we know how
to successfully communicate
between our master list
fragment and the main activity.
And there's one more step.
We need to transfer information
from our main activity
to our body part fragments
to effectively update
their contents.
So when an image is selected
in the master list fragment,
we'll want to store
the list index
to display for each of the
head, body, and leg images
that were selected.
Then display those choices
in the following Android Me
activity.
First, I'll add class
variables to store the location
of the clicked images.
One variable each for the
head, body, and leg images.
These values will
all be in the range 0
through 11, because there's 12
images for each of these lists.
But the click position
goes all the way up to 35,
as we said before, since
the list of all images.
So to get the correct body
part in the correct index,
we have to do some helpful math.
We know that there are 12 images
for heads, bodies, and legs.
So if we divide the
click position by 12,
we can identify
the type of image,
whether it's a head,
body, or leg, and the list
index they are in their
respective fragment image idea
lists.
Here the body part number will
be 0 for the head fragment,
1 for the body, and 2
for the leg fragment.
And the list index will always
be a value between 0 and 11.
Then using a switch
statement, we
can update the index variables
in the on image selected
callback.
And we'll set the correct
index no matter what the case.
Then to actually pass this
information to an Android Me
activity, we'll need to
bundle it up and attach it
to a new intent that launches
a new Android Me activity.
And again a bundle is just
a set of key value pairs.
To actually launch
this activity,
I'm also going to add a
button labeled Next that
moves us from our master list
to the Android Me activity.
So in our master list
fragment we at the bottom
I'll add a Next button,
and I'll wrap both of these
in a vertical linear layout.
I'll give the button the ID
Next button, so that I can
refer to it in our activity.
So back in the
main activity code,
I'll give a reference to that
Next button, and on a click
it will launch a new
Android Me activity.
There's one more task
that I'll leave up to you.
In the Android Me
activity, you'll
have to retrieve the bundle
of information that's
been sent in this intent,
and set the correct list
index for all the
body part fragments.
Once you complete
this exercise, you'll
have a complete phone app.
And we just have
one more exercise
to complete our two
pane tablet layout.
Great job so far.