Now we're
on the homestretch,
and we only have one more task
to complete before our app is
responsive and finished.
The last step is to create a
two-pane layout that appears
on larger tablet screens.
To review, we want the
master list and three body
part fragments to be separate
activities on a small phone
screen.
But we want them side by side
in the same main activity
on a tablet like this.
To implement this
in code will be
similar to how you'd create a
landscape layout or a smallest
width layout, with a
new layout resource
folder that defines a two-pane
layout for a larger screen
size.
For tablets, this means
defining a new layout folder.
And tablet screens have a
smallest width of 600 dp,
so we'll create a
folder for this layout
and name it layout-sw600dp.
Then, in this folder, we'll
create an activity_main XML
file.
This will override the
default activity_main file.
And in here, we'll
define our two panes
as a horizontal linear layout.
We'll start with the master
list on the left side.
Then I'll include a small
divider line and our body part
fragments on the right side.
Like before, I'm
using the fragment tag
to hold our master
list of images,
because this fragment is static
and doesn't change at runtime.
And I'm putting in three
frame layout containers
in a vertical linear
layout on the right side
of the screen for our
dynamic body part fragments.
You'll notice that these have
the same IDs as in our phone
activity_android_me layout.
And the linear layout that
holds all these containers
is called
android_me_linear_layout.
So all this XML code should
look fairly familiar.
Now back to our main activity.
We'll have to distinguish
between this two-pane tablet
case and the
single-pane phone case
so that we can display
the fragments correctly
for all screen sizes.
To track whether this
is in two-pane mode,
I'll create a Boolean
variable named mTwoPane.
Then in onCreate, I'll know
if it's in two-pane mode
by the presence of
the linear layout
that we added in the main
layout file just now.
When the app first
starts in onCreate,
this layout does not yet
exist on a single-pane phone,
but it does on a
larger tablet screen.
So whether it's null
or not indicates
whether this should
be a two-pane
or a single-pane layout.
Then if it is in
two-pane mode I'll
have to populate the fragment
containers with new body part
fragments.
This will be very
similar to the code
in the android_me activity.
I'll get a fragment manager,
and create new body part
fragments for the head,
body, and leg images
that are on screen.
In the two-pane
case, we also want
to get rid of the Next button.
So we'll set its
visibility to gone.
I'll also set the number
of grid view columns
to two, for a better
looking display,
and these are both
just small UI changes.
Getting rid of the button,
and changing our grid view
slightly.
Lastly, I'll have to
handle communication
slightly differently, since
the tablet should not ever
start a new activity when
a list item is clicked.
So let's scroll down
to our callback method,
onImageSelected.
In here we'll want to
update the click behavior
to handle this two-pane case.
In the two-pane case, when
a list image is clicked,
we'll immediately want to
replace the existing body part
fragment with an updated
one with the selected image
resource.
First I'll create an if-else
to separate our two-pane case
for our single-pane phone case.
Then, to replace body parts
fragments dynamically,
we'll be using switch
code as before to identify
which type of image
has been clicked on--
head, body, or leg.
Then create a new body
part fragment accordingly,
setting the correct
resources and image ID,
and replacing the
existing fragment.
Here I've written
the code to handle
the head fragment, case 0.
If a user has clicked
on an image of a head,
this creates a new fragment.
It sets the list of
images and the image ID
based on the click position.
And finally, using a
fragment transaction,
it replaces the
existing head fragment
by referencing the container.
I'll leave it up to you
to complete this code
for the rest of the fragments
in the next exercise.
After you add the code to
replace all types of fragments
when an image is
selected, this should
complete our flexible UI.