(VOICEOVER) I
mentioned before that fragments
are essentially reusable pieces
of UI, similar to a layout
or view group.
And they can be
arranged differently
based on screen size.
They're commonly used to create
single-pane and multi-pane
layouts, depending on what works
best for a given screen size.
For example, here's the Gmail
app, which has a list of emails
and their individual content
appear on different screens
on a phone.
But on a tablet, the list
of emails and the content
appear side by side
because there's
enough room to see them both.
So the Gmail app
layout changes based
on the screen size
of an Android device,
whether that's small
like on a phone
or larger like on a tablet.
And it uses fragments
to define each layout
and use the screen space
efficiently so that everything
is clear and readable.
The same goes for
many weather apps,
which often have a list of days
and separate detailed views
that appear differently on
phone screens and tablets.
Same with the Contacts app
and so many more examples.
A phone screen will
have separate activities
for lists of information
and detailed content views,
whereas a tablet will have these
same views appear side by side.
In fact, this is such a common
pattern that it has a name.
It's called the
master, detail flow,
where the master list of items--
like contact names or emails--
will take up an entire
phone screen but only
the left portion
of a tablet screen.
And the detailed content
pane-- which often shows more
information about a selected
item in the master list--
will take up the entire phone
screen as a separate activity
but only the right portion
of a larger tablet screen.
This is the pattern we're going
to implement for our AndroidMe
app, with fragments that display
a master list of all the custom
Android images, as
well as fragments
that display parts of a detailed
full-body image of the Android.
Then, we'll arrange them in
single-pane and multi-pane
layouts, depending on the
size of the device screen.
So how do we build
something like this?
To implement this
on tablet, we'll
have one main activity that
contains our master list
fragment, the master list of all
images we'll be selecting from.
Then on the right
side of the screen,
we'll have three total
body part fragments,
which make up the head, body,
and leg portions of the custom
Android we want to make.
And on a phone, we'll have the
master list fragment and body
part fragments held in
two separate activities
so that each takes up the
full area of the phone screen.
And we'll see each
clearly and in sequence.
To complete this app,
you'll be provided
with some starting code
and then given tasks
to help you build this final UI.
Next, we'll talk more about why
you'd use fragments as opposed
to simple view groups.
And then we'll dive into code.