After seeing the Android Me
app, you might be thinking,
aren't these android images just
image views and view groups?
Why do we need to
use fragments instead
of using what we already know
about building responsive
layouts?
Well, the real power
in using fragments
is that they allow us to fully
modularize our activities.
You can combine multiple
fragments in a single activity
to build a multi-pane
UI, like on a tablet.
And you can reuse
a single fragment
in multiple activities.
So, separate from simple
layouts and views, a fragment
also has its own life cycle.
It can receive its
own user input events
like clicks or swipes.
You can also dynamically
add or remove them
while an activity is running.
An example where
this is very useful
is in the master
detail flow we talked
about earlier where,
on a phone, we
have two separate activities.
One that holds a master
list of items, then
another that displays
more detailed content.
And a good tablet layout will
have both of these activities
side by side.
However, activities are meant
to be on separate screens
and not embedded
within one another.
So, instead, Android
has fragments
which are designed to be
placed alone or in groups
within a single host activity.
Also, a fragment
doesn't have to be
paired with the same activity
or even the same location
in an activity each
time it's instantiated.
All of these traits,
including modularity,
make fragments extremely useful
for building a flexible UI.