Now we can think of
fragments as mini activities,
as portions of UI each
with their own lifecycle,
but they also have to be
embedded within an activity.
So how does the
fragment lifecycle
compare with the
activity lifecycle,
and how do they work together?
Since a fragment must be
embedded in an activity,
its lifecycle is directly
affected by the host activity
lifecycle.
So as the host activity
moves through its callbacks,
on start, on resume,
on pause, and on stop,
so do any fragments it contains.
And in most cases, you
can move any functionality
you would have put in those
activity lifecycle callbacks
to the corresponding
callback inside a fragment.
There are a few
differences though.
For example, fragments have
additional lifecycle callbacks
that allow them to
be created or removed
in an activity at runtime.
So rather than
building a new view
in on create, as
activities do, fragments
use a different event for
this called on create view.
On create view is where a
fragment inflates its UI,
hooks up any data
sources it needs,
and then returns the created
view to the host activity.
And there's a corresponding
on destroy view
callback that can be called
before a host activity is
destroyed.
With these additional
callbacks, a fragment
can actually cycle through
its whole lifecycle
multiple times as its
host activity is running.
Next, you'll get a little
more info about the fragment
lifecycle and test your
knowledge in a quiz.