OK.
Now that you know a bit
more about fragments
and why they're so
useful for building
a responsive and flexible
UI, let's dive into the code
you'll be starting with.
And let's take a look at what
the final app will look like.
Throughout this lesson we'll
be building an Android Me
app that lets us create
a custom android.
The end result will
look like this.
It lets you select
different images
for the head,
body, and leg parts
of the android from a list.
And when you click
on an image, it
updates how the final android
looks in this layout that
displays the whole android.
So you can select body, legs,
and heads as you choose.
This is the final two
pane tablet layout,
but we'll be starting by coding
up the layouts on a smaller
screen phone first.
It will be up to you to
write most of this code,
but I've provided
some starter code
so that you'll be able to focus
on creating and displaying
fragments.
The code you'll be starting
with includes some image assets
and a utility class that
helps you load the images.
All the images we're using are
in the drawable folder here.
And there are 12 images
each for bodies like this.
Also 12 images for heads, and
12 for different types of legs.
We also have a utility class
called android image assets.
And in here, you're given
ArrayLists of those image IDs--
which are integers-- and
their corresponding getter
methods at the bottom.
getHeads returns
all head image IDs.
getBodies returns all the
ideas for images of bodies.
getLegs returns
the leg image IDs.
And finally, getAll will return
a list of all the image IDs.
Nothing in this utility
class should be changed.
We'll be using these
methods later when
we build fragments and tell
them what images to display.
You'll also start with
a basic activity called
Android Me activity, and a
corresponding, fairly simple
layout.
You'll also see a class
called master list adapter.
This adapter is responsible
for taking in a list of images
and displaying them
as a grid view list,
as we saw on the tablet before.
All this code is
well commented, and I
encourage you to
look around before we
dive into creating fragments.
The instructions for
downloading this starter code
can be found in text
following this video.
Our first task will be to
create a single fragment that
displays the head of our
custom android image.
Let's get started.