The
easiest way to see
how to create and
display a fragment
is to jump straight into code.
Right now, our app
doesn't display anything,
and we'll want to
create fragments that
display our Android body parts.
Let's start by just
displaying the head.
To create a fragment, the
first thing I'll need to do
is define a new
layout file for what I
want the fragment to look like.
This layout will define
what view or views
I want the fragment to contain.
And I'll name this
Fragment_body_part.
And I want this to
display an image
of a head or any
other body part,
and so I'll just have it
be a single image view.
Then click OK to create.
Now, if we look in here, it's
just a single image view.
Now we have our image view, and
I just need to give it an ID,
so I can refer to it later on.
It's a good idea to always
provide a descriptive ID,
so I'll give this image view
an ID body_part_image_view.
And at the top I'll add
a descriptive comment.
Now let's go back to our to-dos.
The next step is to
create a new class,
called BodyPartFragment,
that will display an image
of an Android Me body part.
This Fragment class
will inflate the layout
that we just created.
So in the UI folder,
I'll create a fragment
by creating a new class.
I'll name it BodyPartFragment,
since it will hold the Android
body part images, and its
superclass will be Fragment.
And I'm using the Fragment
from the support library.
Then click OK.
Now we have an empty class
that extends from Fragment.
This extension is
important, because it's
how Android knows to treat this
class, and its lifecycle events
and creation, as a fragment.
Now every fragment will
implement a couple of methods.
The first is an
empty constructor
that's necessary for
instantiating the fragment.
The second is a
method onCreateView,
which is called when the
fragment that we just created
is inflated for display, similar
to onCreate for an activity.
So make sure to implement
both of these methods
for any fragment you create.
In onCreateView is where
we should write code
to inflate the
BodyPartFragment layout.
I'll call this inflated
layout root view.
I'll also get a reference
to the image view
this will display by calling
findViewByID on our body part
image view.
Now I'll also be
able to set the image
resource to be the
ID of whatever image
I want this to display.
For now, let's just
display the first image
in the list of heads.
To get the list we
use our utility class,
AndroidImageAssets,
and we call getHeads.
This returns a list of all the
image IDs we're interested in.
Then finally, we call get
0 to get the first item
in the list at index 0.
We'll later update this code
to display any image we want.
Finally, I'll just
return the root view
that this has created.
Now we're almost done.
We've created the Fragment
class and its layout.
But we need to include some
code in our Android Me activity
that actually
displays the fragment.
This is because
every fragment needs
to be embedded in
a host activity.
So let's go back to our
Android Me activity code.
First, I'll need to define a
place in the activity Android
Me layout file for
our fragment to go.
This is known as a
fragment container.
It's typically a framework
layout of some defined size.
In this case, 180 dp
high, and the full width
of the phone screen.
This defines the space that
a fragment will take up
in a layout, and I'll give
this an ID head_container.
Now that we have a
fragment container,
let's move back to the
Android Me activity code.
In here, in
onCreate, I'll create
a new instance of a
BodyPartFragment, called
headFragment.
Then I'll use something
called a fragment
manager and a transaction to
actually add this new fragment
to the screen.
This transaction essentially
adds our fragment
to the specified container.
And we'll be learning more about
the fragment manager in just
a little bit, so I've
provided this transaction code
in the instructor notes below.
This is mainly so that
you can run the app
and visually see if your
fragment looks like you expect.
So let's run the app
on a phone and see.
And here's our head fragment.
It looks great.
We've coded and displayed
the first fragment.
Next, it will be up
to you to follow along
with the to-dos in the code.
Create a body part
fragment and display it.
And remember, there are three
main parts to this task.
First, creating the layout file
that defines what the body part
fragment looks like.
Second, creating the
corresponding fragment class
that inflates the layout
and defines what image
will be displayed.
And third, displaying
that fragment
through its host
activity using a fragment
manager and a transaction.
Good luck.