Now you've
created and displayed
your first fragment,
and now it's
time to add the rest
of the fragments.
There are two more
body parts to display
(to complete the androidme image)
the body and leg portions.
And you have almost
enough information
to create these without
any more guidance.
But let's go through
in a little more detail
how fragment creation works.
To create or swap out
fragments, Android
uses the FragmentManager.
The FragmentManager
class provides
methods that allow you to add,
remove, and replace fragments
in an activity at runtime.
These are all types of
fragment transactions.
These transactions let you
create a dynamic experience
and help efficiently
add and remove fragments
without you having to
worry about the finer
details of memory management.
An important rule when dealing
with dynamically adding
or removing fragments while
an activity is running
is that your
activity layout must
include a fragment
container in which you
can add each fragment.
This is often an
empty frame layout.
The container is responsible for
defining the size and placement
of a fragment,
since the fragment
doesn't have to take up an
entire screen like an activity.
And when you add or replace
a fragment at runtime,
you'll need to tell the fragment
transaction the container
to place the
updated fragment in.
So containers are needed
if you plan on performing
fragment transactions.
The one case where you will
not need a fragment container
is when you know that your
fragment will remain static,
which means it won't
change during the runtime
of the activity.
Then it will not need
a container layout
because a static fragment
size, content, and location can
be defined and
will stay the same
for the duration of an activity.
And we'll see an
example of this later
on with the MasterListFragment
that displays all our images.
For now, let's get a
little more practice
using the FragmentManager
and dynamically
adding fragments to our screen.