So you've already
seen how to add
a new fragment to an activity.
But let's walk through what
this code is doing line by line.
Inside the Android Me
activity in onCreate,
we've called
getSupportFragmentManager.
This gives us a fragment manager
using the support library APIs.
The manager is responsible
for starting and completing
fragment transactions.
So, using the manager, you
can call a beginTransaction
to start a new
fragment transaction.
Next, you decide
what actions to take.
A callToAdd adds a
fragment and embeds it
within a host activity.
A callToReplace would
replace an existing fragment
through its
associated container.
Well let's change
this back to add,
since we're embedding
it within this activity.
Add and replace are
the two main types
of actions we'll be
using in this app,
but you can perform
multiple behaviors
like a series of
adds, replacements,
or removals by making multiple
calls during the same fragment
transaction.
And when you're ready to
complete the transaction,
you must call commit.
To add our other two
body part fragments,
you'll create two more
containers of the same size
as the head container in the
activity Android Me layout
file where we want to
display the body parts.
So you'll create two more
containers like this one.
This time, giving them
the descriptive IDs
bodyContainer and legContainer.
And back in our Android
Me activity code,
you'll create a new body
part fragment for each
of those body and leg parts.
And I'll actually leave this
portion of the code up to you,
since it's very similar
to what we've done
to display the head fragment.
Next, let's look at how to
change the displayed image.
Right now, in the body
part fragment class,
we set the image resource
to the first head image
in our list of IDs.
But I actually want to be
able to dynamically set
the image to any one
I want to display,
whether that's an image
in the middle of the list
or an image of a body or legs.
So how can I do that?
Well, instead of hard
coding in the list of images
and an index to
display, I can store
this information inside the
body part fragment class.
I just have to create variables
to store that information.
I'll store a list of
image IDs and the index
in that list to display.
And I'll store them
in two class variables
that I'll define as a list named
mImageIDs and an int variable
named mListIndex.
Then I also need to
define setter methods that
let me set the initial
values for these variables
once I create a fragment.
So I'll create public methods,
setImageIDs, and setListIndex
that take in a list of
images to work with,
and the index that
determines which image
ID in the list to display.
And I'll set them to
the internal variables.
Then I'll update my image
resource code in onCreateView.
I'll delete this
hardcoded image resource.
Then I'll add a code that
checks that a list of image IDs
has been set.
Otherwise I'll log a message
saying that the list is null.
At the top of the class, I'll
create a tag for logging.
Then, if the list of
image IDs is null,
I'll create a log
message that says so.
If the list is not null, then
instead of setting the image
resource to the
first head image,
I'll set it to the image
whose ID is in the image IDs
list at the desired list index.
And finally, we actually need
to use these setter methods
in our activity code.
So let's go back to
Android Me activity.
The rest of the transaction
code will remain the same.
So let's see what
this looks like.
Now we see a different
head image displayed.
Next, it will be your job
to do the same thing--
defining and setting variables
for each body part fragment
class.
This includes displaying the
body and leg images, too.
And by the end of
the exercise, you
should have a full body
image of a custom android.