After
that last exercise,
you should now have all the
body part fragments displayed
on screen.
But the app is kind
of boring right
now, so the next thing we'll
do is add some fun interaction.
One common user interaction
is to update the image display
when a user clicks on a fragment
or a view in a fragment.
So I'll be creating a click
listener for our body part
fragment, so that
each fragment can
respond to clicks by changing
the image it's displaying.
The idea is that on
a click, the fragment
will update to
display the next image
resource in its stored
list of image IDs.
You might be used to attaching
click listeners on a view
through an activity,
but remember
that the power of fragments
is in their re-usability
and modularity.
So in this case,
it's a good idea
to handle the click interaction
within the fragment class,
since it repeats for
all body part fragments.
So let's go to our body
part fragment code.
So I'll want to add
a click listener
on the image view in our
body part fragment class.
Then, on a click, I'll increment
the value of mListIndex,
and update the image
resource to the next image
in our list of image IDs.
The image view will
need to be declared
final, since it's being
accessed now by an inner class.
I'll also want to give
our fragment a way
to figure out if it's reached
the end of the list of images
to display.
And if the list index
reaches the value
at the end of the list, I'll
reset the displayed list index
to the first image
ID at index 0.
This way, I can keep on clicking
through, updating the list
index and image
resource to display.
So let's see what it looks
like when I run this app now.
Each body part fragment has
an internal click listener.
And it changes image IDs based
on how many times I click.
So the functionality
looks pretty good.
But look at what
happens when I rotate.
When I rotate the device,
it resets the images.
And I want it to
maintain state, so I'll
want to have a way to save the
current state of the body part
fragments.
Let's go back to our code.
I can do this by overriding the
method, onSaveInstanceState,
and saving the current
variables in a bundle.
And a bundle in this case is
just a set of key value pairs.
I'll want to have this
bundle include the image
list and the current list index
of this body part fragment.
I'll define the strings
as static final string
variables, named
imageIdList and ListIndex.
Then I'll save the bundle of
variables, the imageIdList,
and the ListIndex in
onSaveInstanceState.
I attached the current image
list to the imageIdList string,
and I attached the current
mListIndex to ListIndex string.
So I am storing the
current imageIdList
and the current ListIndex.
Then, at the start
of onCreateView,
if I detect a saved
state, I'll load the value
of these saved variables.
Finally, to complete
the saving state code,
I'll have to go back to
the Android Me activity.
And I'll slightly
modify this code
so that I'm only creating
new fragments if there are
no previously saved fragments.
So I'll wrap this
fragment creation code
in an if statement
that checks if there's
a saved InstanceState.
Now let's run our app again.
Now I'll click on my body
part images and rotate.
This time, the fragment
states are all saved.
Next, it will be your
turn to follow along
with the to do's in
code, and play around
with click interactions.